Simon, Greg mss., 1985-1998 LMC 2820
Lilly Library
Simon, Greg mss.
1985-1998
Lilly Library
Simon, Greg
LMC 2820
1 Box
The Simon, Greg mss., 1985-1998, consist of proofs, drafts, and correspondence relating to Simon's translation of Poet in New York by Federico Garcia Lorca.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2013
Biographical Note
Greg Simon earned his MFA in Creative Writing at Stanford University and has spent most of his life in the Pacific Northwest. In addition to translating the works of Federico Garcia Lorca, Ruben Dario, Gaston Baquero, and others from Spanish into English, Simon has published two volumes of original poetry and numerous essays and reviews in The American Poetry Review, The New Yorker, and other periodicals. Simon and Steve White have also translated the poems of Ruben Dario in Ruben Dario: Selected Writings (2005), Gaston Baquero's The Angel of Rain (2006), and Pablo Antonio Cuadra's Seven Trees Against the Dying Light (2007). Simon's co-editor, Steve White, currently teaches in the Department of Modern Languages at St. Lawrence University.
Much of this collection focuses on Greg Simon and Steve White's translations of Federico García Lorca's (1898-1936) Poeta en Nueva York (1940), written in 1930 and published posthumorously in 1940. He was a poet, playwright, and theater director and a member of the Generation of '27, a generation of influencial poets and authors who incorporated European movements such as surrealism and futurism into Spanish Literature. Lorca was murdered by nationalist forces during the Spanish Civil War. Other famous works include the plays Blood Wedding (1932), The Public (1930), and Yerma (1934).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of typewritten proofs, drafts, galleys, and a small amount of correspondence relating to Simon Greg and Steve White's translation of Lorca's Poet in New York.. Included is the 1988 Spanish edition illustrated by Mario Hernandez, the 1988 1st Edition published by Farrar, Straus and Giroux, an American Publishing Company, alongside correspondence with that publisher. Also included are the 1995-1998 drafts and galleys for the 8th edition of Poet in New York.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by edition.
Literature--translating; Spanish poetry; García Lorca, Federico, 1898-1936
- 1987 Spanish Edition
  - Incomplete Scan of Mario Hernández's Illustratiions, 1987 (Box 1)
- 1988 English First Edition
  - Typescripts 1985-1986 and copy edition text (1/2) (Box 1)
  - Typescripts 1985-1986 and copy edition text (2/2) (Box 1)
  - Early Draft, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Draft, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Draft with handwritten notes (1/2), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Draft with handwritten notes (2/2), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Draft Federico Letters, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Galley Draft (1/2), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Galley Draft (2/2), 1987 (Box 1)
  - Final Galley Draft, 1987 (Box 1)
- 1998 English Revised Edition
  - Revised Galley Edition with Notes, 1995 (Box 1)
  - 1st Pass Proofs (1/2), 1997 (Box 1)
  - 1st Pass Proofs (2/2), 1997 (Box 1)
  - 2nd Pass Proofs (1/2), 1997 (Box 1)
  - 2nd Pass Proofs (2/2), 1997 (Box 1)